FINANCIAL CENTER OPERATIONS MANAGER

Summary

A Financial Analyst role that will utilize my experience and skills to meet the Capstone Corporation Client's *objectives and support commitments to *accounting & financial *management, *delivering *outstanding *integrity, compliance & accountability, operational excellence and continuous *process improvement. **

Experience

Financial Center Operations Manager Jun 2011 to Current

Gms il/4 Hillsboro

- Implementing risk internal controls, drawing conclusions and improving auditing standards and methodologies to better assess and mitigate risk
- Broad knowledge of GAAP and full cycle accounting including A/P, A/R.
- Responsible for banks monthly close and reconciliation ad hoc reporting including coding journal entries Responsible for all transactions processed to include payments, day-to-day deposits, vault settlements, ACH funds transfers and wire transfers.
- Managing banks general ledger approving, posting, disbursing, and collecting funds on BOSS Fast accounting system.
- Quickly leading team in responding to external environments, adapting business processes to our mission and vision.
- Responsible for analyzing and translating financial data to operational objectives, presenting trends and risk/cost analysis to executive team.
- Improving Financial Center organizational design by implementing new business processes that have led to cost effectiveness and new
 efficiencies.
- Championing sound judgment via utilizing critical thinking and problem-solving abilities to resolve complex challenges and escalated issues to meet the needs of internal and external teams.
- Facilitating audit engagements & risk assessments to assess adequacy of controls Supervising, coaching, developing 8 direct reports to meet
 operational performance standards Serving as Financial Center liaison to integrate business partners delivering organizational synergies
 across business functions.
- Managing budgets/expense management to include FTE staffing and overhead resources.
- Overseeing and monitoring activities of vendors in the Banking Center.
- Effective organization and integration skills prioritizing assignments to meet the demands of day to day activities Conducting exit interviews with bank teams.
- Drafting working papers to identify gaps and operational defects.
- Knowledgeable of Credit Card Act, Dodd- Frank Act, U.S.
- Patriot Act, Bank Secrecy Act/AML, Community Reinvestment Act, OFAC Laws, SOX and many other Laws and Regulations that impact Banking and Financial Services industry.
- Accountable for Financial Center administrative operations.

Sales Manager Oct 2009 to Jun 2011

J.C. Penney, Inc i1/4 City, STATE

- Managed the day-to-day operations and leading sales team of 30 team members, engaging in sales leadership and credit investments.
- Engaged in event planning and marketing and inventory flow, set execution and merchandise presentation.
- Assisted in strategic planning for three million dollar facility renovation.
- Planned and devised work schedules, according to budgets and workloads; maintained reports such as budgets and operational.
- Trained, hired and discharged employees observing and evaluating workersÂ' performance.
- Resolved complaints and answered questions of customers regarding services and procedures.
- Developed improved procedures to meet and exceed customer expectations through SWOT Analysis', developing, explaining, and implementing policy, and problem identification analysis.
- Lead forecasting, market analytics and sales team training/development programs.

General Manager Intern Aug 2009 to May 2010

CBL & Associates Properties, Inc i1/4 City, STATE

- Established and maintained a productive relationship with tenants and community by creating long term partnerships.
- Assisted the property leasing executives with new and renewal leasing efforts.
- Directed specialty leasing operations, canvassing, marketing including identifying and qualifying prospective tenants and negotiating license agreements.
- Developed, planned, organized, managed, solicited, negotiated, awarded, terminated, administered, and closed out leases & acquisitions to meet customer and executive needs.
- Collected and analyzed tenant sales data.
- the ability to read, analyze and interpret complex documents Adaptive to a changing work environment to meet the demands of a changing industry to drive profit margins.
- Oversaw the activities of contractors, vendor personnel and suppliers; negotiated and monitored contracts for compliance and controlled costs; monitored all expenditures.
- Utilized corporate resources to increase the effectiveness and quality of services provided to the property owners.
- Completed cost analysis for center & assisted in procurement plans.
- Directed the preparation and implementation of budgets and strategic plans.
- Prepared financial reports as required and monitor rent collections.
- High degree of human relations skills to work with diverse teams Interpersonal ability to communicate effectively both orally and in writing.

Education

Master of Business Administration, Present Walden University GPA: Magna Cum Laude Magna Cum Laude Present

Master of Science, Management, Accounting Apr 2014 University of Maryland University College il/4 City, State GPA: Cum Laude Cum Laude Management, Accounting

Bachelor of Science Degree , Business Management May 2011 Virginia State University i1/4 City , State GPA: Cum Laude Cum Laude Business Management

Skills

accounting, acquisitions, administrative, ad, A/P, auditing, Banking, budgets, business processes, coaching, Interpersonal, contracts, cost analysis, Credit, critical thinking, Draffing, event planning, Fast, Financial, forecasting, funds, general ledger, drawing, human relations, inventory, investments, leadership, Managing, marketing, market, negotiating, organizational design, organizational, personnel, presenting, problem-solving, procurement, profit, coding, quality, read, reporting, sales, settlements, sound, staffing, strategic plans, strategic planning, Supervising, translating, vision

Professional Affiliations

Advisory Board Member, Virginia State University Reginald F. Lewis College of Business Bank of America Maryland DC Metro Area Volunteer Financial Management Leadership Strong Communication & Critical Thinking Analytical and Problem Solving Results Driven/Internal Audit Highly Detailed Oriented